sc.gov 2012-12-02

# Privacy and Security Policy - SC.GOV

## Privacy Policy

SC.GOV is a creation and a service of the State of South Carolina (“State”). It is operated and managed under a long-term contract with a private company, South Carolina Interactive, LLC (“SCI” or “South Carolina Interactive”). The term “we” in this policy refers to the State and SCI. 

Your privacy and security are our highest priority. Providing electronic access to state government information and services, while maintaining privacy is a specific objective of SC.GOV’s Strategic Business Plan.

SC.GOV collects from users only the personal information necessary to provide the information and services requested by them. Personal information in our possession is maintained and used in ways that respect individual privacy. Employees are educated about the importance of protecting personal information and consumer privacy, and only authorized employees are officially granted access to personal information.

SC.GOV will not disclose personal information collected from users to private third parties unless the law requires such disclosure. Laws do exist in the State of South Carolina to ensure government is open and that the public has a right to access appropriate records and information possessed by a government agency. At the same time, however, there are exceptions to the public’s right to access certain records in order to preserve the privacy of individuals. Such exceptions are authorized by both State and Federal law. Information collected from users by SC.GOV, similarly to information collected during in-person visits to a government office, may be subject to inspection and copying by the public, unless an exemption exists in law. In the event there is a conflict between this Privacy Statement and a State or Federal law governing the disclosure of public records, the applicable law shall control.

The Family Privacy Protection Act of 2002 prohibits persons or private entities from using personal information obtained from State agencies for commercial solicitation purposes. A person knowingly violating this prohibition is guilty of a misdemeanor and subject to the penalties specified in S.C. Code Ann. Section 30-2-50(D). 

Depending on the situation, we may collect the following information about visitors to our Web site: 

  * the domain name 
  * the e-mail addresses of those who communicate with us via e-mail 
  * aggregate information about which pages consumers access or visit 
  * information volunteered by the consumer, such as survey information 

This information is used to improve the scope and content of the state's services on the Internet, and in some cases to respond to you.  

### Cookies 

Any web page or application at this site that uses cookies will identify itself as such. Cookies are short and simple text files that are stored on a user's computer hard drive by web sites. They are used to keep track of and store information so the user does not have to supply the information multiple times. The information that is collected through cookies at this site is handled in the same manner as other information collected here. You can configure your web browser to refuse cookies or to notify you when a web site attempts to send you a cookie. You can also check your hard drive for cookie files and delete them from your computer. However, cookies allow you to take full advantage of many of South Carolina’s eGovernment services, and we suggest you consider setting your web browser to accept cookies from those sites hosted by South Carolina Interactive.  

### Email Correspondence 

E-mail messages will be treated the same as any other written communication. They may be subject to public inspection or legal disclosure. Please do not put confidential and personal information such as social security number, date of birth, bank account and credit card information, mother's maiden name or medical information in your e-mail communications to the State or South Carolina Interactive, LLC. Your privacy cannot be protected or insured by the State or South Carolina Interactive during email or unsecured web form transmission.

If you send an E-mail message or complete a web form which contains personal information, we collect and store the following information:

Any personally identifying information, which you choose to provide (for example your mailing address), in an electronic mail message or web form requesting information, any comments on policies, issues, or events you send in a Live Help session. Information collected in this manner is used solely for information and, in some cases, to respond to you. An email automatically includes your email address and certain routing information, including your internet server. **  
**

### Links to Other Web Sites

This web site has links to many other web sites. These include links to web sites operated by other governmental agencies, nonprofit organizations, and private businesses. Many of these sites may not be subject to the South Carolina Code of Laws, or may operate under different privacy standards. Visitors to those web sites are advised to review the privacy statements of those sites. Neither the State nor South Carolina Interactive are responsible for any content on a linked site.

### Live Help 

The Live Help service is the SC.GOV portal's live customer service application that allows visitors to talk with customer service representatives in real-time. 

Certain information is collected and maintained in regards to the Live Help service. In addition to IP address, browser type, date and time of the visit, and the referring webpage, transcripts of the chats are saved for statistical, demographic, and/or customer service purposes. Some information is also collected through chat surveys on a volunteer basis.

Please do not put confidential and personal information such as social security number, date of birth, bank account and credit card information, mother's maiden name or medical information in your Live Help communications to the State. Your privacy cannot be protected or insured by the State during Live Help, email or web form transmission.

When you open a Live Help session a cookie is placed on your system and the Live Help operators are notified that a visitor has entered the Live Help site. At this time, operators can see the following information about your session: 

  * Browser type and version 
  * Host address 
  * Host IP number 

The purpose of the cookie is to enable the Live Help system to associate each Live Help session with the previous session so that each operator will be able to assist you without requiring that you repeat information previously provided. You are not required to enable cookies to use Live Help. The cookie will not track any of your browsing activity beyond this page.

Transcripts of the Live Help sessions contain the following information: 

  * Session date 
  * Session start and end time 
  * Operator name 
  * Visitor name as entered 
  * Browser type and version 
  * Host IP number 
  * The text of the discussion 
  * Exit interview responses 
  * Topic 
  * Email address if a transcript was requested 

### **Contact Information**

The State welcomes comments regarding this privacy statement. Please convey any questions or concerns to:

SC.GOV   
The Official Web Site of the State of South Carolina   
1301 Gervais Street, Suite 710   
Columbia, SC 29201-3326   
1.866.340.7105 

Revised June 4, 2008

## Security Policy

SC.GOV is a creation and a service of the State of South Carolina (“State”). It is operated and managed under a long-term contract with a private company, South Carolina Interactive, LLC (“SCI” or “South Carolina Interactive”). The term “we” in this policy refers to the State and SCI.

SC.GOV uses the Secure Sockets Layer (SSL) protocol to safeguard your sensitive personal information, including your credit card number, during online transactions.  SSL protocol is the industry's accepted form of encryption and it provides the highest level of protection possible for Internet communications. Your transaction is secured using this widely accepted form of encryption from your personal computer to the SC.GOV computer processing your request.

The SC.GOV processing computers are located behind a firewall that employs security features. Your credit card information is not stored on a state government database and only authorized employees have access to your credit card number for card processing purposes.

If you have trouble purchasing securely at our website, then you may be behind a firewall or using a proxy server that doesn't allow for secure transactions.

Revised October 28, 2005
